<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on belchak.com</title>
    <link>https://belchak.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on belchak.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2016 21:05:17 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://belchak.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>the fastest way to success</title>
      <link>https://belchak.com/post/2016/04/21t210517&#43;0100/the-fastest-way-to-success/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2016 21:05:17 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://belchak.com/post/2016/04/21t210517&#43;0100/the-fastest-way-to-success/</guid>
      <description>I recently heard a quote by Tom Ziglar on a Ziglar Show podcast that went like this: &amp;ldquo;The fastest way to success is by replacing bad habits with good habits.&amp;rdquo;
This got me thinking. What kind of bad habits do I have, and what do I want to replace them with?
I started writing down a list of bad habits that I have, and discovered that a lot of them went like this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>tips for new or not so new managers</title>
      <link>https://belchak.com/post/2016/02/28t114930&#43;0000/tips-for-new-or-not-so-new-managers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2016 11:49:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://belchak.com/post/2016/02/28t114930&#43;0000/tips-for-new-or-not-so-new-managers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So you&amp;rsquo;ve just gotten that management role for which you&amp;rsquo;ve been gunning for months or years now. Congratulations! You&amp;rsquo;re a few weeks in, and you&amp;rsquo;re realizing that you are in over your head, and that maybe this isn&amp;rsquo;t all it&amp;rsquo;s cracked up to be. You&amp;rsquo;re looking for advice, and I&amp;rsquo;ve got some for you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;have-a-story-you-want-to-tell&#34;&gt;Have a story you want to tell&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people call this a vision. I like the concept of &amp;lsquo;telling a story&amp;rsquo;. Think about what you want your story to be six months, a year, and 3 years down the road. Use some of your thinking time to put yourself into the future and look back on the time period you&amp;rsquo;re going for. Think about what the journey looked like, and write it down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some questions to ask when coming up with your story:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What does your team look like?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What have you accomplished together? What &amp;lsquo;next-level&amp;rsquo;          things did you achieve?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How have you grown?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What direct impact have you had?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How are things better than when you found them?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;you-don-t-have-to-know-everything&#34;&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t have to know everything&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In David Marquet’s book &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.co.uk/Turn-Ship-Around-Building-Breaking/dp/0241250943/&#34;&gt;Turn the Ship Around&lt;/a&gt; he mentions how he had studied for over a year to take command of a certain type of submarine. He studied how everything worked, and was an absolute expert on every facet of that type of submarine. At the very last minute he was reassigned to one of the most underperforming submarines in the US Navy. To add insult to injury, it was a class of submarine that he was not familiar with. He learned some valuable lessons about how you don’t have to be an expert, and you don’t have to know everything to be an effective leader. In fact, the opposite was true. He was more effective because he empowered his crew to make decisions based on the information they had (which is often much more than the leader has.) This allowed him to be freed up to focus on more strategic issues affecting him and his crew. Ultimately, his crew and submarine went on to become one of the highest rated crews in US Navy history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a great talk where he shares some of these ideas:
&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/OqmdLcyES_Q&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>making sensu work with graphite</title>
      <link>https://belchak.com/post/2012/08/02/making-sensu-work-with-graphite/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://belchak.com/post/2012/08/02/making-sensu-work-with-graphite/</guid>
      <description>Like many companies, I&amp;rsquo;m sure, we&amp;rsquo;re investigating using Sensu for monitoring and Graphite for metrics collecting. The docs for making these two commuicate together over AMQP are pretty good except for one thing.
Using the docs that I&amp;rsquo;ve read, when you start up Sensu first with its default options for AMQP, and then start up Graphite to read from that queue, Graphite will crash every time it tries to create the exchange.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>migrating from wordpress to octopress</title>
      <link>https://belchak.com/post/2012/07/31/migrating-from-wordpress-to-octopress/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://belchak.com/post/2012/07/31/migrating-from-wordpress-to-octopress/</guid>
      <description>WordPress is awesome, why&amp;rsquo;d you switch? So, I&amp;rsquo;ve been really hating WordPress as a blog engine lately. Tons of spam, lots of emails from spam accounts signing up and trying to post comments, etc. We had some discussion at the office recently about what blog engine to use for our corporate blog, (we ended up using WordPress) but through the process I decided to evaluate Octopress as an approach to static content serving for my personal blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jira and campfire integration</title>
      <link>https://belchak.com/post/2012/01/21/jira-and-campfire-integration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://belchak.com/post/2012/01/21/jira-and-campfire-integration/</guid>
      <description>I have been working on migrating my company&amp;rsquo;s Pivotal Tracker to JIRA. We love most of the features of JIRA, but we were really missing the nice updates to our Campfire room to tell us what is going on with our issues.
Sure, we could use an RSS feed plugin for Campy, but that is not real-time enough.
I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to write a huge plugin just to send messages to Campfire (it seems like such a simple thing to do!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>problems with ipv46 hosts in osx lion</title>
      <link>https://belchak.com/post/2011/07/27/problems-with-ipv46-hosts-in-osx-lion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://belchak.com/post/2011/07/27/problems-with-ipv46-hosts-in-osx-lion/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, you end up doing a lot of testing in virtual machines. I run several VMs that do various different tasks for me so that I don&amp;rsquo;t have to sully my Mac with packages I rarely need, etc. So what I do is create a VM and give it a local hostname defined in my /etc/hosts file.
Recently, after my upgrade to OSX Lion, I started running into an issue where it would take over 5 seconds to connect to any of my VMs using any protocol (SSH, HTTP, etc).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>re enabling key repeat in osx lion</title>
      <link>https://belchak.com/post/2011/07/23/re-enabling-key-repeat-in-osx-lion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://belchak.com/post/2011/07/23/re-enabling-key-repeat-in-osx-lion/</guid>
      <description>I have recently upgraded to OSX Lion, and I have to say that I love everything about it. Except for one thing. In many apps, the key repeat has been disabled in favor of the new press-and-hold popup for getting alternative characters.
This is fine for most apps, but for apps like PyCharm where I use vi key maps, it becomes very, very frustrating.
I came across this little tip to re-enable the key repeat, and my life is measurably better (first world problems, I know&amp;hellip;).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>campy the python campfire bot</title>
      <link>https://belchak.com/post/2011/06/24/campy-the-python-campfire-bot/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://belchak.com/post/2011/06/24/campy-the-python-campfire-bot/</guid>
      <description>We use a Campfire at Needle for our day-to-day communication between our tech team members and other business members. We really like Campfire&amp;rsquo;s ability to store files, conference call and keep transcripts even when you are not logged in. We get GitHub commit messages, Pivotal Tracker story updates and more scattered in our conversations.
These one-way updates are very nice, but I thought it would be nice to be able to have a bot that sat in the channel and could take commands from anybody and do more complex tasks for us without us ever having to leave Campfire.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>workfit standing desk</title>
      <link>https://belchak.com/post/2011/03/04/workfit-standing-desk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://belchak.com/post/2011/03/04/workfit-standing-desk/</guid>
      <description>A few months ago, I started investigating the health benefits of standing while I work at my computer. The benefits are myriad, and include:
 More calories burned. Standing at a desk while you work can actually burn around 300 calories per day more than sitting.
 Standing at a desk helps people with back problems. Humans were not made for sitting, and doing so for long periods of time can be really hard on your hips and lower back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>unit testing django with a nosql backend</title>
      <link>https://belchak.com/post/2011/02/07/unit-testing-django-with-a-nosql-backend/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://belchak.com/post/2011/02/07/unit-testing-django-with-a-nosql-backend/</guid>
      <description>In my previous post about unit testing for django, I laid the groundwork for how to unit test any django application. One nice feature that django includes with its test framework is the test database syncing. Even better is if you are using South to do database migrations - it will run the migrations in your test environment for you.
However, what if you are using a NoSQL database backend like MongoDB, Cassandra, CouchDB or something similar and you aren&amp;rsquo;t using the Django ORM?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>unit testing your django application</title>
      <link>https://belchak.com/post/2011/02/05/unit-testing-your-django-application/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://belchak.com/post/2011/02/05/unit-testing-your-django-application/</guid>
      <description>Unit testing is a very important part of any software project. It helps you know that the new code you are deploying works, and isn&amp;rsquo;t going to blow up in your face. It also helps you feel good about changing large chunks of code without destroying everything you&amp;rsquo;ve done for the last 3 years.
Unit testing with django is as simple as pie. The documentation is very good, and you can learn a lot about more advanced testing methods from the python documentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>code completion for python and django in vim</title>
      <link>https://belchak.com/post/2011/01/31/code-completion-for-python-and-django-in-vim/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://belchak.com/post/2011/01/31/code-completion-for-python-and-django-in-vim/</guid>
      <description>VIM has been my editor of choice for at least 15 years. I love how fast I can edit files, perform menial tasks, and wreak general havoc on any code project I am working on at any given moment. One of the things that I have missed about VIM from an IDE perspective has been code completion (a.k.a. &amp;ldquo;IntelliSense&amp;rdquo;). I have spent a lot of time on websites and man pages trying to figure out syntax and function names for several types of languages, and just recently discovered a long-included feature of VIM called omni completion, or Omnicomplete.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>django database migrations with south</title>
      <link>https://belchak.com/post/2011/01/27/django-database-migrations-with-south/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://belchak.com/post/2011/01/27/django-database-migrations-with-south/</guid>
      <description>I have been using django for web development for almost a year now, and I just recently started using South to do database migrations. To be fair, most of the work that I have been doing with databases has centered around MongoDB and schema-less document stores instead of a traditional RDBMS. Since Django does not come with any database migration tools, my standard approach was to make sure that my models are completely thought out before running the manage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>removing old ssh fingerprints from your known_hosts the quick and easy way</title>
      <link>https://belchak.com/post/2011/01/27/removing-old-ssh-fingerprints-from-your-known_hosts-the-quick-and-easy-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://belchak.com/post/2011/01/27/removing-old-ssh-fingerprints-from-your-known_hosts-the-quick-and-easy-way/</guid>
      <description>Ever have this problem? You just rebuilt a machine, and when you go to SSH into it, you get the following message:
@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@ @ WARNING: REMOTE HOST IDENTIFICATION HAS CHANGED! @ @@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@ IT IS POSSIBLE THAT SOMEONE IS DOING SOMETHING NASTY!  Many people just go edit their ~/.ssh/known_hosts file and carry on. But there is a faster/better way!
OpenSSH comes with a command called ssh-keygen that allows you to generate and manage all your keys, including your ssh fingerprints.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>automatic mongodb backups to s3</title>
      <link>https://belchak.com/post/2011/01/20/automatic-mongodb-backups-to-s3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://belchak.com/post/2011/01/20/automatic-mongodb-backups-to-s3/</guid>
      <description>One of the big problems with hosting your own database solution is that you have to do backups for it on a regular basis. Not only do you need to do backups for it, but you need to also keep backups offsite. Luckily, Amazon S3 allows a cheap and easy solution for your offsite backups.
I found a shell script solution for handling MongoDB backups, but it only does local backups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>problems with facebook api and m2crypto</title>
      <link>https://belchak.com/post/2011/01/19/problems-with-facebook-api-and-m2crypto/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://belchak.com/post/2011/01/19/problems-with-facebook-api-and-m2crypto/</guid>
      <description>After doing some crypto updates to a django application that I am working on, I discovered that the Facebook API was dog slow for retrieving any query using HTTPS. Turns out that the M2Crypto library apparently hijacks the SSL processing of urllib and mucks everything up. Thanks to this handy blog post, I was able to fix my Python implementation of the Facebook API and get things speeding along again.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>